根据Seuss博士同名小说改编
Based upon the book by Dr. Seuss
五月十五日
On the fifteenth of May
Nool丛林里
in the jungle of Nool
酷暑难耐
in the heat of the day
在沁人心脾的池塘里
in the cool of the pool
他戏水享受着丛林的巨大乐趣
He was splashing enjoying the jungle's great joys.
Horton 这头大象听到了一个微弱的声音
And Horton,the elephant heard a small noise.
- Horton!　- Horton!
- Horton!  - Horton!
早上好 同学们 准备好了吗?
Good morning, class. Are you ready?
好了!
Yeah!
快上船吧!
Jump on board!
当心了 下面的!
Look out, below!
Tommy上船了
Tommy's on board.
Katie 你在吗?
Katie, you there?
好了
OK.
就是它了
There it is.
这是丛林里最为奇特的物种之一
This is one of the jungle's most amazing creatures.
绿盲蝽
The leaf bug.
为了躲避捕食者
In order to protect itself from predators
他把自己伪装成一片树叶
It disguises itself as a leaf
这家伙抓得可真紧
This one's got quite a deep grip.
来吧 小东西! 别害羞!
Come on, little buddy! Don't be shy!
我想我弄错了 孩子们
I guess I was mistaken, Kids.
这里显然没有绿盲蝽
There are obviously no leaf bugs in this area.
即便是... 噢！他们爬到我身上来了
Even a per... Oh! They're on me.
看 这儿有呢
Look at, there are bugs
我想我吸进去了一只
I think I swallowed it.
快喷出来! 呃 喷不出来
Shoot up! Uhek it's not coming.
把它扯出来
Pull it out.
呃 好吧
Uh, OK.
在一旁唧唧哼哼的 就是坏脾气的袋鼠
Then, humphing her nose was sour Kangaroo.
这家伙总认为自己比谁都聪明
A type who's convince she knows better than you
她自诩为Nool的丛林之王
She made every law and then forced every rule
她制定了每一条法规 并强制别人执行
as self conclaimed head of the jungle of the Nool.
妈妈 我为什么不能和别的小朋友一起玩?
Why can't I play with the other kids, Mom?
我跟你说过多少遍了?
How many times have I told you?
丛林容不得兽行
The jungle is no place to act like a wild animal.
天呐 那个Horton总这么古怪的?
My, that Horton certainly is eccentric?
孩子们从他身上学到了不少东西呢
And that children are learning so much from him.
学会了如何成为低能儿
Learning to be a bunch of a hell brain halfwits.
这就是为何我的Rudy得在育儿袋里接受教育的原因
And that's why my Rudy is pouch schooled.
在袋鼠还在冷嘲热讽时
So, while Kangaroos still there sneering a sneer
Horton 这简直是我生命里最精彩的时刻
Horton,how it's the best time of my life.
你打算再教我们什么呢?
What are you gonna show us then?
那粒小浮尘又飘到了Horton的耳边
Once again the speck floated right by Horton's ear.
他又听到了
And he heard it again.
只是一声非常微弱的叫唤 好像是有小东西在求救
Just a very faint yelp, as if some tiny person were calling for help.
你知道他怎么想的吗?
And you know what he thought?
他想 准是有人住在那粒小浮沉上
What he thought there must be someone on top of that small speck of dust.
甚至可能有一家子住在上面 绝对有可能
Or even a famly. It just might be so.
拖儿带女的一大家子
A family with children just starting to grow.
我想活下去!
I wanna live!
我得走了 Katie 交给你了
I got to go. Katie, you're in charge.
等等!
Wait!
回来!
Come back!
再来一个 再来一个 再来 再来
One more, one more, one more, one more.
- 啊 有人来了  - 给我看看
- Ah here someone coming.  - Get here those.
- 等等!  - 拉警报!
- Wait!  - Sound the alarm!
借过! 小心被踩到!
Excuse me! On my stamp feet!
抱歉 Wickershams
Sorry, Wickershams.
我保证待会儿会把这里清理干净!
I promise I'm gonna clean all this up later!
拿箭来!
Bring the arrow!
我喜欢香蕉味满溢的早晨
I love the smell of the banana's in the morning.
香蕉炮!
Bananing Hoe!
别这样 伙计们! 我们都是哺乳类的!
Come on, guys! We're all mammals!
我感觉外交关系就要破裂了
I feel diplomatic process is beginning to break down.
你在这儿
There you are.
I'll catch it. catch it.
我要抓到它 抓到它
嗨 孩子们
Hi, kids.
好了
There
现在你安全了
Now you're safe.
我知道 我听到你说话了
I know I heard you say something.
我就知道
I just know it.
你在哪儿?
Where are you?
- Horton?　- 抱歉
- Horton?  - Uhoo, sorry.
我只是... 哈
I just...ah.
有粒浮尘
There was this speck.
而且... 他们在呼救
And the... they called up for help.
- 然后我...  - 这浮尘...
- And I was...  - The speck...
呼救了?
called out for help?
浮尘怎么可能会呼救 我是说
Well not the speck. I mean
这太荒谬了
That's ridiculous.
你是这么想的?
Is what you thought I've been?
当然 浮尘怎么可能会呼救 拜托
No,the speck can't call out for help. Come on.
现实点儿吧!
Get real!
不
No.
There's a tiny person on that speck and he needs my help.
有个小人儿住在这上面 他需要我的帮助
荒谬
Absurd.
怎么可能有这么小的人儿
There aren't people that small.
哇哦 也许不是他们小
Whoa, maybe thay aren't small.
也许...
Maybe...
是我们太大
We're big.
- Horton!  - 不! 真的 想想
- Horton!  - No! Really, think about it.
要是真的有人
What if there is someone
正在高高的上方
way out there,
俯瞰我们的世界呢
looking down on our world right now.
对他们而言 我们也只是浮尘而已
And to them, we are the speck.
然后有人走过来 他说
And then this someone else come along, he say,
"噢 怎么可能有这么小的人儿
"Oh, there can't be people that small."
前面那个人就说
And the first guy would say
"那你认为我是在撒谎?"
"Are you calling me a liar?"
后面个人就说
And the second guy would say
"要真的 当然会相信
"If the shoe fits wear it,
而你是个傻子"
and now that fits a blind."
前面个人休息吃晚饭
and the first guy pick supper break.
要是想听下面部分 你最好先把育儿袋拉上
And you might wanna zip up the pouch for this next part.
好吧 胖子!
Alright, fat boy!
- 你要来点儿...  - Horton?
- You want some of there...  - Horton?
浮尘上什么都没有
There is nothing on that speck.
但我听到了
But I heard.
是吗? 真的? 天呐!
Did you? Really? Oh my!
那我怎么听不到
Then how come I don't hear anything.
好吧?
Well?
如果你既看不到 听不到 又感觉不到某种东西
If you can't see, hear, or feel something
那这种东西就压根儿不存在
it doesn't exist.
而且在Nool丛林里 相信虚构的小人儿的存在 不是我们该做的
And believing in tiny imaginary people is just not something we do.
也是我们所不能容忍的
Or tolerate here in the jungle of Nool.
是吗?
Really?
因为我亲耳所闻
Cause I verified I really tried
我会找到的
I can find somebody
- 相信我的人的  - 你不准这么做
- who believe what I'm saying.  - You will do nothing of the sort.
不准再跟任何人提起这个谎言
You will not breathe the word of this lie to anyone else.
特别是孩子们
Expecially the children.
我不会让你用你的荒谬言论 去毒害他们的心灵的
I do not want you poisoning their minds with this nonsense.
国有国法 Horton
Our community has standards, Horton.
如果你还想在这里混 你就得好好守这里的规矩
If you wanna remain a part of that I recommend you follow them.
祝你有美好的一天
Have a nice day.
好的!
Alright then!
我会... 谨遵教诲
I'll ah...take that an advisement.
多谢提醒
Certainly appreciate your input.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我明明听到你的声音了
I know I heard you.
就像我确定我脸上长着鼻子一样
It was just as clean as nose on my face.
对了
That's it.
或许你听不见我说话!
Maybe you can't hear me!
因为你的耳朵肯定很小
Of course your ears must be tiny.
我得大点儿声!
I need to speak up!
你好!
Hello!
现在那些高高在上的人
Now some people out there
或许如我所了解的那样
might think I know who
他们会同意坏脾气袋鼠的话
they find they agreed with that Sour Kangaroo
"不可能会有跟老鼠一般大小的人"
"There can't really be people as small as a mice"
当然会有 的确有
Well there can. And there are.
因为Horton是对的
Becuase Horton was right.
你好!
Hellow!
这句"你好"随风飘扬
That single "Hello" traveled all the way down
飘到浮尘上 花朵上 飘进小镇的喷泉里
to the speck,to the flowers, to the fount of the small town.
这小镇叫无名镇 因为这里住着无名氏
The town known as Whoville for there live the Whos
这里安居乐业 充满喜庆
Really happy in safe, knowing only good news,
他们从没意识到 他们的世界只是苜蓿花上的一粒浮尘
unaware that their world was a speck on a clover,
他们从没意识到 这种甜蜜的生活或许会成为过去
unaware the sweet life they knew might be old
无名镇的镇长 是一个叫McDodd的男人
The Mayor of Whoville a man named McDodd
他鞠躬尽瘁 公正严明 但也有点古怪
who's devoted and faired and little bit odd.
镇长和他的妻子有一大堆孩子
The Mayor and his wife they had children to spare.
九十六个女儿 这儿有一些 那儿还有一些
96 daughters, some here and some there.
这九十六个女儿都需要爱护和教育
96 girls to love, 96 girls to teach.
而镇长在每个女儿身上只能花个几秒钟
But the Mayors have only few second for each.
爸爸 我的无名镇史考试拿了优
Daddy, I do better than best on my whostory test.
啊 无名镇史 我倒背如流
Ah, whostory. I remembered well.
真是我的乖女儿
That's one of my girls.
她老用我的梳子?
Her is has been using my hairbrush?
她才老用我的梳子
Her is has been using my hairbrush.
看 那边!
Look, over there!
好了 好多了
There, all better.
我能有部无名电话吗 爸爸?
Can I please have whophone, daddy?
班里每个同学都有
Everyone else in my class has one.
噢 是吗? 每个同学都有?
Oh, really? Everyone?
- 好吧! 我会考虑的  - 爸爸 看啊！爸爸快看!
- Aw! I will think about it.  - Daddy, look! Daddy look!
牙此!
Toos!
宝贝儿 念"齿" "牙齿"
It's "th" sweetheart. It's "Tooth"
无名镇的传统很与众不同
In Whoville tradition unlike yours or mine
一般来说 镇长的长子就是他的继承人
Mayor's oldest is the next Mayor of line.
那么这里又会是谁来继承衣钵 掌控大权呢?
And who was the oldest lead and stand tall?
是JoJo 镇长的儿子 最小的孩子
It was JoJo, his son, the smallest who all.
JoJo 有什么大新闻?
So, JoJo, what's what's shaking?
有什么事儿发生吗? 有什么变化没?
What's happening? What's the word?
你我都很清楚
Now to you or to me, it's finally clear
JoJo并不想继承父位
that JoJo did not want his father's career.
但镇长却完全不了解
But the Mayor pressed forward completely illuded.
JoJo默默地坐在一旁 昏昏欲睡
And JoJo just sat there in silence and lude it.
噢 JoJo!
Oh, JoJo!
- 嘿! 为什么他的时间要多些?  - 不公平!
- Hey! Why this he get more time?  - That's not fair!
儿子! 嘿!
Son! Hey!
他干嘛不说呢?
And why didn't he speak?
我想 他是担心 要是他说出来的话
Well I think the lad was frightened if he did,
会让他爸爸失望
he might let down his dad.
你知道什么才是让人敬畏吗?
You know what's awesome?
这就是让人敬畏!
This is awesome!
看看墙上挂着的这些伟人像
Just look at the men and the women hanging on these walls.
你 我的儿子 是这个延续了几个世纪的家族的继承人
You, my boy, are part of family legacy that spans centuries
你知道吗?
You know what?
你祖父是无名镇的镇长
Your grandfather was Mayor of Whoville.
而你的曾祖母 也是
And, your great grandmother, that's right.
一直可以追溯到你的
All the way down to your
曾
Great
还不止
Not so great
曾 曾
Great, Great
曾 曾 曾
Great, Great, Great
曾!
Great!
祖父!
Grandfather!
我希望有一天能加入他们
Some day I hope to join them.
成为伟人之一
Be one of the Grates.
我告诉你 JoJo 成为镇长是一件最伟大的事情
I tell you JoJo there is nothing like being Mayor.
我可以签署决议 批准法令 拟出财政预算
I get to sign resolutions, approve ordinances, submit budgets.
而在美食游行中
And in the edible parade
我是唯一一个坐在巨人头顶的人
I'm the one siting on top of the giant people.
而有一天
Some day
那个人就是你 JoJo
That can be you too, JoJo.
有一天 你会戴上镇长的羽饰
Some day you'll be the one wearing the Mayor crest.
你只要...
You just...
你只需要...
You just need to...
你明白我的意思吗?
You know what I mean?
好的 聊得不错!
OK. Good chat!
很高兴跟你聊天
I'm glad that we had this talk
虽然从头到尾都只有我一个人在说 很好
That I'm continuing now by myself. Good.
噢! 这儿 放这儿好了
Oh! There. There are to become fit.
Morton不会有事儿的 不会有什么事儿的
Nothing wrong with this，Morton. Nothing wrong with this.
只有你 我 还有这粒灰尘
Just you and me，and the speck
一起来闲聊
Shouldn't a breeze.
我们要团结 我们是一伙的
We're club. We're group.
要是有分歧 我们可以投票解决
We can take a vote on issues.
对社会来说 我们是
We can be a secret to society
- 控制世间海盗力量的秘密武器  - Horton?
- to control pirate's power in the world.  - Horton?
别人都无法加入
And no one else can join
除非他们戴上有趣的帽子
Unless they wear funny hats.
听着 Horton!
Listen, Horton!
主席准许Morton兄发言
The chair recognizes his brother Morton.
我很高兴你发现了这粒浮尘
I am really happy you found this speck in all.
但你自己知道就好了
But you might wanna think about keeping it to yourself.
呃 什么 什么?
Um, what, what?
你在跟那朵苜蓿花说话?
Are you talking to what clover.
那可不大对劲儿
That doesn't look good.
你知道什么才是不对劲儿的吗?
You know what doesn't look good?
你 说得好像浮尘不存在一样
You, talking about the speck like the speck isn't even there.
浮尘可没说过你的坏话
Speck never said nothing bad about you.
但是 嘿!
But hey!
上帝保佑你幻想的优越感
Good luck with your illusional superiority.
那只是一粒灰尘 你可以随便说它对我有什么想法
You know, the speck can think anything you want about me. It's a speck.
哇!
Wow!
我明白了
I see what's going on here.
Morton 不管我和灰尘变的有多亲密
Morton, no matter how tight this speck and I get,
它都不能代替你
the speck could never replace you.
我只能说到这了
I'm only sad that I would have to explain that at this point.
好了Horton 我感觉好多了
Well, that's awesome Horton. That really helps.
尽量别张扬 回见
Just try to keep this to yourself. I'll see you later.
尽量哦
Try.
嗨 Horton? 你鼻子上拿的什么?
Hey, Horton? What's you got in there?
什么? 没什么
What? Nothing.
我们什么都没做
We're not doing anything.
- 我们是独自一人  - 干吗用我们?
- We are totally alone.  - Who's we?
我们? 什么我们? 我有说过吗?
We? What we? Did I say that?
我只是... 噢 不 我绝对不会那样说的
I just... Oh, no. I would never say that
那样不就暗示我和某人一起了么
because that would imply that I was with someone and not alone.
好吧 千万不能告诉其他人
OK There is a story you can't talk to anybody
我是说真的
I mean it.
If anybody finds out about this, it could be very very bad.
如果让其他人知道了 会非常非常糟糕
我也不知道为什么
I'm not sure why.
我们不会告诉别人
We won't tell anyone.
就算我们告诉别人了 我们也会叫他们不要告诉别人的
And if we do, we'll tell them not to tell anyone.
好极了!
Perfect!
好吧 当时我正在洗澡
OK. I'm taking a bath, right.
因为我的皮肤容易干燥 还有点脏
Cause my skin gets kind of dry. My roof gets ashy...
Horton承认了他发现的灰尘
While Horton came clean about the speck that he found
以及他是怎么拯救它的
How he saved it and nearly drowned.
镇长早上上班的时候
The Mayor set off on his morning commute
发现今天跟平时不太一样
and noticed things not quite the same on his route.
请不要责怪Horton 因为他也不知道
But please don't blame Horton for he didn't know
灰尘外一次剧烈的颠簸
that a strong bump above...
我像这样跳到水里
I do it in the water like this...
灰尘里却是一场地震
Was a big bump below.
嗨 Joe! 别太拼命!
Hey, Joe! Don't work too hard!
哈! 这种豪华公寓不可能自己建好的
Ah! These luxery condos they have gone themselves.
嘿 你看 原来他们真的能自己建好
Hey, you look at that. I guess they do build themselves.
噢 奇迹
OK, that happened.
镇长知道
Now the Mayor knew it was his job
将他发现的异象公布于众 是他的职责
to convey the unusual things that he noticed that day.
但是有个问题
There was one problem.
尽管他有强烈的信念
Though his will was strong
- 你迟到了  - 谢谢 Yelp小姐
- You are late.  - Thank you，Miss Yelp.
无名镇从未出过事
Nothing in Whoville had ever gone wrong.
我们从不贪求 我们珍惜所有
We have all that we need. We need all that we've got.
我们喜欢无名镇 我们非常喜欢
We like it in here Whoville. We like it a lot.
大家都忙于无名镇百年庆的筹备 所以...
We're all very busy with WhoCentennial's coming up. So...
赶紧开完会吧
Let's break this meeting to order.
镇长先生 你给我们带什么好消息了
Mr. Mayor I presume you have some good news for us.
是有消息 但我不知道
Well, it's news. I don't know
到底算好消息还是坏消息
if we need to go label it good or bad anything like that.
最近我发现无名镇有奇怪的现象
The thing is I have noticed some odd goings on in Whoville lately
好的奇怪的事?
Good on goings on?
例如 地震 龙卷云
Well, you know. Tremors, clouds swirling in the sky.
安全起见 我们是不是考虑...
And it seems to me just be safe, we might wanna consider...
推迟百年庆?
Postponing the WhoCentenia?
考虑什么?
Consider what?
推迟百年庆?
Postponing the WhoCentenia?
什么?! 大声点!
What?! Speak up, man!
推迟百年庆 行了吗?
Postponing the Whocentennial, alright?
我们要庆祝无名镇百年来的欢乐和谐
We're about to celebrate 100 years of Whoville happiness in harmony.
而你想推迟庆典?
And you want to postpone the celebration?
那如果无名镇不安全呢
Well, what if Whoville's not safe.
无名镇从没出过事!
Nothing ever goes wrong in Whoville!
过去不会 将来也不会有事!
Never has and never will!
你个蠢材!
You bloodly boob!
蠢材
Boob.
百年庆典将照计划进行!
The Whocentennial will proceed as planned!
镇长是个傻蛋
The Mayor was really being an idiot.
从现在起 只有微笑
It will be all smiles from now on.
姐们 我已经有一万五千点击率了
Girl, I got 15,000 friends already.
什么? 你说不像我?
What? What you mean it don't look like me?
跟我是一个模子刻出来的
That look just like me.
十年前... 等等
Ten years ago... Wait a minute, hold on for a second.
把我当傻蛋?
Treats me like an idiot?
我不是傻蛋
I'm not an idiot.
我看起来像傻蛋吗?
Do I look like an idiot?
- 你不会想听答案的  - 我不是傻蛋
- You don't want me to answer that.  - I'm not an idiot.
说我是蠢材?
That's nerve call me a boob?
我从不会骂别人蠢材
I would never call somebody a boob.
他才是蠢材
He is a boob.
看看你 呸
Look at you, yuck.
瞧瞧你的脸
Look at your face.
我打赌
And I bet.
把这钉书机摁你脑袋上 你就不会好看了!
You don't look so good with this staple on your head!
- 谢谢 Yelp小姐  - 不客气
- Thank you, Miss Yelp.  - You're welcome.
你好?
Hello?
谁在那? 出来 吃我一拳
Who's you that? Got go out. I'll punch you.
你好?
Hello?
你是谁?
Who's there?
我是... 镇长
Hmm... This the Mayor.
镇长?
The Mayor?
哈 看 是镇长!
Uh, look at this Mayor!
我就知道
I knew it.
我就知道 我就知道 我就知道
I knew it. I knew it. I knew it.
灰尘上有生命
There's life on this speck.
灰尘? 什么灰尘?
The speck? What speck?
是...
Well, um...
我不知道怎么跟你说 但是...
I don't exactly know how to tell you this. But...
你生活在一粒灰尘上
You're living on a speck.
我不想反驳你
Well, I hate to disagree with you.
下水道的声音
Oh, voice from the drain pipe.
可我生活在无名镇
But, I live in Whoville.
那无名镇就是一粒灰尘
Well, then the Whoville is a speck.
好了 严肃点 你是谁?
Right. OK Seriously. Who is this?
是学会计的Bert吗?
Is this Bert from accounting?
不是 我是Horton
No. This is Horton.
我是只大象
I'm an elephant.
好吧 Horton 一听就是假名
OK Horton, fake name.
你在哪?
Where are you?
从你站的地方看?
Well, from where you standing?
我想我在...
I guess I'm...
天上
in the sky.
和你比 我简直就是巨人
Compare to you I'm enormous
其实也不是
which is saying something
因为我最近在游泳减肥
because I slim down quite a bit. I swim.
在我的世界中 你的世界被固定在一朵花上
Your whole world fits on a flower in my world.
噢 这里也能装得下你 Bert
Oh, man, this is even inclusion for you, Bert.
不相信吗?
Don't believe me?
看看我把你放在树影下会发生什么
Watch what happen when I put you in the shade
- 一派胡...  - 暗
- This is absolutly impossi...  - Dark.
亮
Light.
暗
Dark.
亮
Light.
Dark, light, dark, light...Dark!
暗 亮 暗 亮...暗!
亮!
Light!
还不明白?
Don't you see it?
我们正处于某种神奇的宇宙交汇中
We're in the middle of some kind of amazing cosmic convergence.
两个迥异的世界
Two vastly different worlds.
奇迹般的交汇在一起!
Miraculously crossing path!
我的大世界!
Mine colossal!
你的小世界
Yours mini to cure.
竟然产生了沟通
Yet, somehow we've marriage to make contact.
想想看 太神奇了
If you think about it, it's pretty amazing.
你那还好吧?
Is everything OK down there?
噢 我... 我不知道
Oh. I... I don't know.
你说呢...
You tell me...
灰尘在你手里
You're the one holding the speck.
灰尘在我手里
I'm the one who's holding the speck.
灰尘竟然在我手里
I'm not holding the speck.
别担心 镇长先生
Don't you worry, Mr. Mayor.
请等一下
Hold, please.
这意味着什么?
What at all this means?
镇长想不出来
The Mayor hadn't the clue.
因此 他去Larue博士的办公室
So he went to the office of Dr.Larue.
想借用一下专家的聪明脑袋
Brainest brain on the staff at Whouse.
Larue博士!
Dr. Larue!
噢 这太疯狂了
Oh, this is crazy.
噢 是镇长先生啊
Oh, Mr. Mayor.
我能帮你什么?
Ah, how may I be a assitance?
我不知道 呃
I don't know. Hey.
我就想知道
You know I just wondering
如果说我们的世界是一粒
If our world will stay tiny speck
飘在空中的小灰尘
floating to space,
我们怎么才能证明?
how would we know?
噢 干嘛问这种问题?
Oh, why would you ask something like that?
噢 没什么 随便问问
Oh, no reason, no reason at all.
我甚至都不记得 不 我记得
I don't even remember. Yes I do.
听着
That you know what,
有人跟我说
some guy was talking to me
那人不是天上的大象 而是地上的一个家伙
not an elephant in the sky, a guy on the ground
哈 那可能会产生几种结果
Ah, there would be several ramifications
是好的结果吗?
Good ramifications?
一粒小灰尘
A tiny speck.
是啊 小灰尘
Uhhuh, yeah, tiny speck.
飘来飘去...
Floating around...
已经发生了莫名其妙的地震
Well, we'd have inexplicable tremors.
诡变的天气
Dramatic changes in the weather.
如果最终不能达到某种稳定状态
And if we didn't eventually achieve some sort of stability
我们的世界会 毁灭
our world would be destroyed
毁灭!
Destroyed!
毁灭 噢 毁灭 崩溃了
Destroyed, oh destroyed. No somehow.
Horton?
噢 不 我是Danny Horton正在忙
Ah, no. This is Danny. Horton is busy right now.
开玩笑呢 是我
You, I'm joking. That's me.
我们完了
Ah, We're doomed.
听着! Horton!
Listen! Horton!
看来我需要你帮点小忙
Turns out I need your help a little bit.
很明显 如果任由那粒灰尘四处飘荡
Apparently if that speck keeps moving around,
我们的世界就会湮灭
our whole world could be obliterated.
因此
Ahuh So,
我需要你为我们无名氏找个安全稳定的家 越快越好
I need you to find us Who's safer more stable home and fast
没问题 镇长先生
No problem, Mr. Mayor.
让我看看...
Let's see...
那里看起来不错
That's a nice view.
喂 还好吗?
Hello, is everything OK?
上面怎么了?
What's going on up there?
整个丛林都危机四伏!
This entire jungle is a house of death!
噢 等等
Oh, wait.
那里不错
There's good spot.
这时 Horton看见Nool山顶
And it's then Horton saw at the top of mountain Nool
有一个绝佳的小山洞
a small cave that was peaceful and quiet and cool
那里向日葵欣欣向荣
where sun flower grew proud and tall from the ground.
在那里 每个无名氏都会
There he knew every Who would be safe,
平安无事
would be sound.
我找到了 镇长
I found it Mayor.
最完美的地方
The perfect place.
就在那
Right up there.
- 在Nool山顶  - 镇长先生?
- On the top of the mountain Nool.  - Mr. Mayor?
我希望我们能...
I wish we could...
喔呵呵 哈 真有光泽 啊哈哈
Ohho, Ah, Shiny. Ahha.
无名镇委员会正等着你
The Whocentennial Committee is waiting for you
检查美食游行的大肉丸
to look over the giant meat ball for the edible parade.
并且参加无名镇的晚宴
Oh, and then you will do at the dinners for your Whowill Canal.
在每个词前加"无名"
You know, sticking Who in front of everything
并不能加深意义
doesn't make it heard last.
只是浪费时间!
Just waste time!
我不想去
I don't wanna go.
听着 Horton 我得走了
Listen, Horton. I got to go.
看来大肉丸出事了
Apparently there's problem with the giant people.
你去当心肉丸吧
You just take care that meatball, Sir.
把事交给我吧
And leave the freaking out to me.
就这样 Horton开始了他的漫漫旅行
So, then Horton began his long pairless track
决心拯救灰尘上的小世界
determine to save the small world on the speck.
Horton充满忠贞 富有仁爱之心
Horton was faithful and soul working kind.
我抓住你了
I got ya.
他是勇敢的英雄
He was a brave hero.
我会保护你的
I'll protect ya.
至少他是这么想的
At least in his mind.
我们必须隐身 潜行
We must become invisible. Travel silently.
因为有敌人 他们企图摧毁我们
For there're forces. They would seek to destroy us.
你以为这样就能阻止我 哼!
So, you think you can stick up on me, Huh!
很明显 你根本不是我的对手!
It's clear that you're no match for my ticky kei!
看来你对抽树枝很在行
I see you will master the way of snapping branch.
看筋斗!
Watch me tumble!
Horton! 我们上!
Horton! Let's go!
你很敏捷 Horton 但是袋鼠派来了猴子
You are fast, Horton. But the kangaroo has monkeys.
看我耍这些猴子
I will make monkeys of these monkeys.
这是他们的宿命 啊哈哈!
It is their destiny, Huh uh!
喔呀! 吃我一记冲击波!
HoiYat! My Tumble! My Tumble!
Horton是大英雄 哈!
Horton is the Greatest Hero of them all, Ha!
- Horton!  - Morton! 攻击!
- Horton!  - Morton! Go!
呀 Nool山在那边!
Oh, mountain Nool is that way!
冲到Nool山顶
To the top of the mountain Nool.
冲啊 我就是这样想的
I sensed the fighting. All way I hope.
噢 抱歉伙计
Oh, sorry little fella.
你不会有事的
You'll be fine.
我只是在想象
Just the killing thought.
- Horton!  - Horton!
- 快看啊!  - 跟上!
- Look!  - Go go go!
我们都找到一朵有无名氏的苜蓿
We've all got own clovers with flowers on them.
我的世界里住的都是小马驹
In my world everyone's a pony
他们啃彩虹 追蝴蝶
and they all eat rainbows and poop butterflies
那可真可爱 Katie
That's beautiful, Katie.
虽然有点奇怪
In a really weird way.
我的世界是Jessica岛
My world is called Jessica land
每个人都崇拜 Jessica女王 Jessica就是个美人
Everyone worships queen Jessica because Jessica is the beautiful.
Jessica 太棒了
Jessica, that was awesome.
Rudy?
Mom, be careful!
Mom 小心点!
我最好的朋友David就在上面
My best friend David grows up on there.
- Rudy 这上面没有人　 - 什么?
- Rudy, no one lives on this.  - What?
这是不可能的
It's not possible.
那个Horton是个危险分子
That Horton is a menace.
妈妈 妈妈 求你了 你真是莫名其妙
Mom, Mom, please. You're so weird.
- 不要对我这样嘛 　- 宝贝 呆到袋子里去
- Don't do this to me.  - Honey, go to your room.
Horton!
漂亮
It's good.
你以为你在干吗?
What do you think you're doing?
啊 你有麻烦了
Ha, you got some worlds of trouble.
你忘了我们谈过的吗?
Have you forgotten what we discussed?
哦 当然不 我是个大象 大象好记性
Oh, no. I'm an elephant. And elephants never forget.
我们天性好记性
It's a curse, really.
我全记在脑子里呢
I remember I was on my head.
你说 我记着
And you said and I looked up.
你说你在干什么?
And you say what are you doing?
我说关于这个灰尘的
And I said the thing about the speck.
然后你拉我的耳朵
Then you pull my ears.
- 拍我的前额  - Horton?
- And you fork in a fore head.  - Horton?
你干了什么?
What You did?
把苜蓿给我 Horton
Give me that clover, Horton.
马上
Now.
不!
No!
不?
No?
对
Ya.
你确定你真的要干架吗 Horton?
Are you sure you wanna fight this fight, Horton?
我保证你会迅速落败 而且很难堪的
Becuase I promise you will get very ugly very fast.
你好好想想吧
And you need to ask yourself.
真的要和我作对吗?
Do I really worth put myself through this?
为了朵苜蓿?
For a clover?
照我说的办吧 Horton?
Take after me, Horton?
你不会的
You don't.
那么 交出来吧
So, hand it over.
不! 我不会把他交给你的
No! I can't give it to you.
灰尘上确实有人
There're people on this speck.
生活着很小的生物
Granted very small people.
但是 生命就是生命
But a person's person.
不管大小
No matter how small.
你太过分了 Horton
You just crossed the line, Horton.
我要让你付出代价
And I'm gonna make you pay.
Horton威胁着我们的生活
That Horton is a menace.
他迫使孩子们使用想象力
He has those kids using their imaginations.
真有病
It's sick.
好吧
Alright.
I got to get this speck up to the top mountain Nool ASAP.
我要把灰尘送到Nool山上去 "ASAP"(越快越好)
虽然不知道什么意思
Whatever that means.
可能就是说 "动作要敏捷漂亮 大象"
Probably "act swiftly awesome, pachyderm."
我是说这有什么难的
I mean how hard can it be.
这简直就是直接通往死亡的小道
It's just the straight plummet to certain death.
这个...
This looks...
有点不稳啊
kinda precarious.
不?
No?
不用担心
No need to worry.
很明显他们造桥时
Obviously when they build the bridge like this
他们会考虑大象会通过这里
they take into account the elephants will be corssing here.
好的 感觉不错
Alright. Feel good.
我只是... 喔 哇
I'll just get... Woo Waaa
没事的!
You'll alright!
("勇气") 嗯 的确是那样
("COURAGE") Um, That's true.
好的
Alright.
你好 镇长先生 今天怎么样?
Hello and how are we today, Mr. Mayor?
说 啊
Say Ahh.
请漱口
Wrench, please.
呃 这些木板该换换了
Eh, I think a few of these wood that keep stand need to be replaced.
我只要想着我很轻
I just need to think light.
I'm light as a feather.
我要像羽毛一样
好重的羽毛啊
Heavy feather.
好了
OK.
就疼一下下
This will just pinch little.
我要比羽毛还轻
I'm lighter than a feather.
什么比羽毛还轻?
What's lighter than a feather?
哈! 空气!
Haah! Air!
没有更轻的了
There's nothing lighter.
这是显而易见的...
So, it stands to reason...
我吸入越多的空气我就
get the more air I have
越轻
the lighter
I'll be.
下一位
Next, please.
没事了 刚才太恐怖了
Alright. It was absolutely terrifying.
我要再试一次
If I just right some on
千万别害怕
drawing not to panic.
刚才真的好险
That could've been a disaster.
现在感觉棒极了
I feel really good right now.
这是我实现目标的好兆头
It is my new sense of purpose.
啊 没事了!
Uh alright!
嘿! JoJo 我要你帮下忙 能帮下我吗?
Hey! JoJo I need your help. Can you help me?
好吧 很好
OK. Great.
好的 首先 我要你去女孩寝室里
OK. First. I need you go to the girls' room.
拿下把手 收好所有的藏品
Take down the handle and shut it all the collection
别老看着胳膊啊
Stop looking in arm.
把Holly收集的电灯泡收起来 然后
Put away Holly's light bulbs collection and then
看管好所有会被打破或打碎的东西
you know what，just take care of anything that might break or shatter.
好吧 看个够吧
OK, take a good long look.
明白了吗?
Got it?
谢谢了 JoJo
Thanks, JoJo.
这儿
Here. I know.
还有这儿
And here.
啊 天哪!
Uh Yaaa!
嗨! 你回来晚了
Hi! You're home late.
哦 对不起 亲爱的 只是...
Oh, sorry Honey, I was just...
- 牙医弄坏了我的胳膊  - 那怎么样了?
- having some dental works on my arm.  - So, what was that?
Nedd!
你在干吗?
What are you doing?
你说什么呢?
Wa What do you mean?
我不是侦探 Nedd
Well, I no detective, Nedd.
但是你挂在吊灯上
But you are hanging from the chandelier.
我只是想这样会好点
I just thought it might look better
如果睡觉时不被东西砸到的话
somewhere it can't fall on us and crashes our sleep.
到底怎么了?
What is going on?
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, Honey.
你是否有过那种感觉 你被人监视着?
Did you ever get the feeling that you're being watched?
啊... 应该有过
Am... Ya, sure.
我想是
I suppose.
那么你想过监视你的可能是...呃...
And then you get feeling that maybe that thing watching you is... Ah...
一头巨象?
A giant elephant?
啊..
Am...
你有没有那种奇怪的感觉
You know, how you can that weird feeling
你生活在一个小小的灰尘上?
that your world actually a tiny speck?
我先前跟你提到的那头大象
And then the elephant that I talked about earlier
正在带着粘在花上的灰尘转悠
he's carrying it around on a flower.
当你发现这个后
And you realize
如果你告诉别人 他们反而认为你疯了
then if you tell anybody they think you're crazy.
但你仍旧有责任保护他们的安全
But you still feel the responsibility to keep everyone safe.
你知道这种感觉吗?
You know that feeling?
啊...
Am...
我想 我得说不了
You know, I'm gonna have to say no.
你明白我的意思吗?
Do you know that feeling?
不!
No!
呀啊!
Yar!
哦! 我想歇歇了
Wow! I'm meet the time to hit the hey, I guess.
亲爱的 我知道你压力很大
Sweetheart. I know you're under a lot of stress.
如果你看见大象和花朵 那没关系
And if you're seeing the elephants and flowers, then fine.
别跟别人说
Just don't tell anyone else that story.
好吗? 要知道
OK? And remember.
还没到世界末日呢
It's not the end of the world.
世界末日?
The end of the world?
Horton 呼叫镇长 Horton 呼叫镇长 镇长回话 完毕
Horton, the Mayor. Horton, the Mayor. Come in Mayor, over.
Horton?
我这听得不清楚
I get terrible reception here.
这样行不?!!!
How about this?!!!
我扯着嗓子喊!!! 能听见吗 现在?!!
If I get up all calls!!! Can hear right, NOW?!!
是! 收到!
Yeap! Roger that!
我们到达安全地点了吗?
Are we get that safe place yet?
快了
Almost.
我十分肯定最糟糕的部分已经过去了
I'm pretty sure the worst parts are over.
大象汇报完毕
This is your elephant speaking.
坐稳了 享受旅程吧
Just sit back and enjoy the ride and
我们马上就会愉快地到达Nool山
we all are happy to the mountain Nool no time.
不行 你不能再吃冰激凌了 回去
No, you can't have ice cream. Go back there.
那是谁?
Who's there?
- 那边还有其他人吗?  - 那是我妻子和孩子们
- Is there someone else there?  - Well, that's my wife and kids
你成家了
You have famliy.
确实
I do indeed.
一个漂亮妻子 96个女儿 还有1个儿子
A beautiful wife, 96 daughters, and one son.
好大一家子啊
Hohohoho, busy guy.
我们共用一个浴室 你知道那是什么吗?
Then we all share one bathroom. You know that is?
当然 我怎么会不知道
Ya. Don't I know it.
浴室
Bathroom.
Nedd?
什么?
What?
Sweetheart. You know you're on the roof, right?
亲爱的 你知道你在屋顶 是吗?
你现在马上去睡觉 爸爸有点不舒服
What's have to know is you need to go to bed. Daddy's having a break down.
Nedd? 你到上面干什么?
Nedd? What are you up to now?
我去哄孩子们睡觉
I was just about put the kids bed,
我马上下来
when I got off the roof.
对 这就是我要做的
And I that's the that's what happened right.
- 爸爸?  - 什么?
- Daddy?  - Yes?
- 我能喝杯水吗?  - 当然
- Can I have a glass of water?  - Of course.
- 我也要 我也要 我也要...  - 好的
- Me too, me three, me four...  - OK.
嘿 JoJo! 哇哦
Hey, JoJo! Wow.
好多水 这么多杯水 我正想见到你呢
A lot of liquid. A lot of liquid. Just the person I wanted to see.
我记得我们好久没有眼神的交流了
Yeah. I've realize that we have not been seeing eye to eye lately
都是我的错 真的
and most of it is my fault. It's true.
你知道我想做什么吗?
You know what I've been trying to do?
我把我的希望强加到你身上
I have been trying to impose my vision of your future on you.
我们要说清楚了
What me make this perfectly clear
JoJo 你想干什么样的镇长 你就干什么吧
JoJo, you can be whatever kind of Mayor you wanna be.
亲力亲为的 强硬少语的 坦率直言的 由你自己做主
Hands-on, strong and silent, outspoken, it's up to you.
好 真好
Well, good
我感觉好多了
I hear so much better.
我看好你啊 好好干吧
I am expecting big things from you young man. Make things.
好了 晚安
Alright. Good night.
谈话愉快!
Good stop! Good talk.
然后 JoJo不再孤单伤心了 不对爸爸的误解失望了
Then, JoJo snuck out feeling lonely and sad and tragedy of misunderstood by his dad.
他这样解脱了以后要去哪?
And where was he going in such a lay down?
要到无名镇废弃的天文塔去
Up to Whoville's abandoned star study tower.
一个能让他感到安心和自由的地方
A place where the boy felt contented and free.
一个可以实现自我的地方
A place he could be what wanted to be.
里面有什么 我暂不介绍
And what was inside there I'd say if I could.
但在外面的世界 袋鼠可不是什么好东西
But up above，the Kangaroo was up to no good.
我能出来吗 妈妈?
Can I come out now, Mom?
不行 Rudy 呆到袋子里
No, Rudy. Stay in the room.
- 但是 妈妈?  - 呆在里面
- But, Mom?  - Stay inside.
Vlad Koff先生在吗?
Mr. Vlad Koff?
吃饭中 勿扰
Eating, go.
我知道你很忙
Yes. I realize you're busy.
我需要你帮忙
But I need your help.
关于Horton的
It's Horton.
他对苜蓿着迷了
He's become obsess with a clover.
甚至认为上面住着小人儿
And he get actually thinks there are little people on it.
我要那朵花消失
I want that colver destroyed.
当然可以 这是个大买卖
Sure, what a big deal this is.
对你来说 哥们
For you, bro.
我可以自己干 但身为女人
I'd do it myself. But being a lady
我可不想弄脏我的手
I prefer not to get my hands dirty.
但我听说你干这种事一向保险
But I hear you have no problem with there.
是
No.
没问题
No problem.
很简单
Easy busy.
但...
But...
我是要开价的
I will only do this for a price.
作为交换 我要一对新的...
In exchange for a brand new pair...
不用了
No.
就这个
This
- 小袋鼠  - 妈妈?!
- little kangaroo.  - Mom?!
别吵 Rudy
Quit, Rudy.
妈妈要好好考虑下
Momy is thinking it over.
谢谢了 但是 我又考虑了一下
We'll thanks but, on second thought
最好还是找Wickersham兄弟吧 他们很乐意效劳
I think I'm going to have the Wickersham Brothers take care of this for me.
是啊 当然 Wickersham 他们也能做类似的事
Yeah, of course, Wickersham, I mean, they're quasi operation.
他们... 等下! 不!
You know, they'd... Wait! No!
你不能找Wickersham
You can't go over Wickersham.
不 不 不 不 Wickershams很称职的
No No. No no no. Wickershams would be perfect for this job.
但 他们是猴子 他们没有威胁性
But, they are monkeys. It's not scary.
不管怎样 谢谢了 下次吧
Ah, thanks anyway. Maybe next time.
等等!
Wait!
我会这样对待那朵宝贵的苜蓿
Here is what I gonna do to the precious clover.
我会抓住它
I will take it.
我会压碎它
I will crush it.
我还会把它给吞了
And I will devour it.
竟然比看上去大的多 等会
Bigger than it looked. One second.
我的天啊
Holy moly.
然后我再把它吐出来
Then I will regurgitate it.
然后...
Then...
我再把它给吞吃了
I mean I devour it second time.
总共吃两次
So two times devour.
听起来不错
Sounds nice.
但是我还是去和Wickershams谈谈吧
But I think I'll talk to the Wickershams.
等等
Wait.
最精彩的部分来了
Here is best part.
整件事我会...
I do all...
做得干净利落
Gracious.
免费的 兄弟
That's free, bro.
你认为怎么样?
What do you think?
- 成交  - 耶 太好了 谢谢
- Deal.  - Yes. Score. Thank you.
不会让你失望的
You won't regret.
市长?
Mayor?
开门啊 市长先生!
Open up, Mr. Mayor!
市长先生!
Mr. Mayor!
夏天飘雪啦!
It's snowing in the summer!
是啊
Yes.
的确是
Yes, it is.
天气有了不可思议的转变
It's a dramatic change in the weather.
好像我们在某一个灰尘上在空中漂移
As if we're on a speck floating to space.
我不知道你是怎么知道的 但是 你就是知道了
I don't know how you knew. But, somehow you did.
无名镇就要大难临头了
And Whoville is headed for disaster.
- 哦 Horton  - 什么?
- Oh, Horton.  - What?
啊 没什么 我已经在想办法了
Ah, nothing. I'm on it.
拯救无名镇的人是我们的责任
It's up to us to save the people of Whoville.
雪真是不吉利的东西
Snow is not lucky.
还不... 停
That's not... Stop.
好吧 还有没有人了?
OK. Anybody else?
太好了
Good.
不 不 快别玩了 这不是什么好玩的
No no. Don't join it. This is not fun.
这是危险预兆
Uh, this is sign of doomed.
小可爱 来 不 不不不
Oh, sweety, that's. No. No no no.
危险! 危险!
Danger! danger!
别再玩了!
Stop having fun immediately!
这很危险的
This is dangerous.
好吧
OK.
Horton?
嗯? 什么?
Uh? What?
嘿 你好啊
Hey, there.
我们有大麻烦了
We're in big trouble down here.
还是发生了 在盛夏的时候竟然下雪了
It's happening. It's snowing in the middle of summer.
这是世界末日!
It's end of the world!
挺住
Hold on here.
我知道你们的问题所在了
I think I know what your problem is.
好了 有没有好一点?
There, get better?
看起来你成功了
That seems you have worked.
呃 我是不是闻起来有点花生味儿?
Ehuh. Do I smell peanuts?
嗯 我最喜欢吃花生了
Yes, they are my favorite snack.
就是有点费事
But they tender linger.
喔! Debrick 不要
Ohho! KUh. Debrick, No.
啊哦 坚持住 市长先生
Oh. Hang on Mr. Mayor.
我或许得干上一仗
I may have to put up a fight.
受惊的大象可是会危险的
Frightened elephant can be very dangerous.
好吧!
Alright!
你来啊 伙计
You come down the under, buddy.
你是不是活腻了?
You hungry for trouble?
我不会让你轻易逃脱的
I don't know how you can easy self by.
来打一架啊
Take a fight.
我讨厌跑步
I hate running.
Morton!
- 别这样!  - Horton!
- Don't do that!  - Horton!
Horton? 别... 你在这啊
Horton? Don't... There you are.
我们有麻烦了 等等 停 等等 你听见了没?
We got trouble. Wait. Stay. Wait. Can you hear that?
没有 我在这 好吧 听着 不 开始
No I'm here. OK. Listen. No, go.
袋鼠疯了 傻了
Kangaroo has gone nuts, bananas.
她散布消息说你应该滚出Nool丛林
She's telling everyone that you should be kicked out of Nool.
她真那样说?
She said that?
我还以为我们是朋友呢
I thought we're friends.
说了 她去找Vlad了
Well it is, she's gone to Vlad's.
Vlad Vlad 我认识两个Vlad
Vlad. Vlad. I know two Vlads.
是那个坏蛋Vlad还是那个会做饼干的松树Vlad?
Is it the bad Vlad or the bunny Vlad that makes the Cookies?
对啊 Horton 她派一个会做饼干的松鼠来对付你
Yeah, Horton. She's sending you a bunny with cookies.
我想我们可以假设不是那个坏蛋Vlad
I think we can assume it's not bad Vlad.
嗯 好决定!
Yeah, that's good call.
除非你一点也不怕他那巨大的利爪
So, unless you're cool with giant razor sharp claws,
你就不需要对付他了
There be not fights up your body,
如果我给了她苜蓿
if I give her the clover.
不可以
I can't.
我向市长保证过了
I promised the Mayor.
我言必行 行必果。
I meant what I said. I said what what I meant.
而且大象都是百分百认真的
And an elephant's faiths were 100%.
求你了 为了我 就这一次 百分之九十九认真就好啦
Please, for me, just this once, be faithful 99% of the time.
我做事从不认真
I've never gone 99% on anything.
可我也是令人敬畏的 照我说的做吧
I think I'm awesome. So come on.
我言必行 行必果!
I meant to what I said and I said what I meant.
我不得不说
I'm gonna say it.
在还没有发生之前你是可以那样做
You can do that all days it's not happen then.
- 大象是百分百认真的  - 对啊
- An elephant's faithful 100%.  - That's right.
那是我的密语 我的座右铭
That's my code. My motto.
谢谢你的警告
But thanks for the warning.
座右铭 好吧
Motto. OK.
快看天空 注视着天空
But watch the skies. Keep watching the skies.
市长 你得把所有人集合到广场上 现在!
Mayor, you need to get everyone on the ground,now.
- 二 三 四...  - 快拉警报
- Two, Three, four...  - I wanna sound the alarm.
我们很有可能...
There's a good possibility we maybe...
被巨大的恶鸟攻击
maybe attacked by a giant cannibalous bird.
什么?
What?
有很小很小的可能是饼干兔子
There's small chance it could be bunny with cookies.
但我可不敢保证
But, I wouldn't count on it.
坏消息
Oh, they are formidable words.
你还在吗?
Are you there?
在 不 主意很不错 只是...
Ya, no. That's a great idea. It just...
要想全部动员 我得先得到市委的许可
in order to get everyone mobilized I need the O.K. of the city council.
他们从来都不肯听我的
And they never listen to me.
我老被叫蠢材 都好几次了
I've been called boob. Several times.
- 我做不到  - 你必须得和他们谈谈 市长
- I can't do it.  - You have to talk to them,Mayor.
好吧 听着
OK. Listen.
坏蛋Vlad
Bad Vlad.
坏蛋Vlad!
Bad Vlad!
肯定不会是兔子了
That is definitely not a bunny.
躲过他了
Lost him.
想要甩开他 我就甩开了
Mean to lose him. And I lost him.
这棵树真是的 别这样!
This tree for real, come on!
挺住 无名镇! 这会是场硬仗!
Hang on, Whoville! This is gonna get rough!
你死到临头了
Now you're going to dead end.
看我的致命一击
Get ready for the best.
别追我!
Leave me alone!
不要! 坚持住!
No! Hold on!
我知道他会别处跳出来的
I just know he's gonna jump out somewhere.
嗨?
Hello?
棋友啊
Chess mate.
我该把苜蓿拿走了
Now it's time for me to take clover...
再去碾碎里边那些可怜人...
and crush all the little people on a two sang...
对不起 我该下去了
Sorry. This is where we get off.
啊 正中我的嘴!
Ah, right in the beak!
打得挺准的
Ah. Cool line.
先不考虑这些
Usually I can think those things to later.
- 市长?  - Horton
- Mayor?  - Ah, Horton.
你还好吧?
Are you OK?
啊
Ah.
还可以
Well, more or less.
- 发生了什么? 恶鸟来了?  - 嗯 它袭击了我
- What happened? The bird?  - Ya, it attacked me.
市长 你的人都很危险
Mayor, your people are in danger.
你知道吗 我决定了
You know what, I'm gonna do it.
我打算走出去 告诉他们发生了什么
I'm going to go out there. And tell them what is going on.
太棒了 那就快点 行动起来
Perfect. Now quick. Get go on.
嘿 市长先生! 出事了!
Hey, Mr. Mayor! Something's wrong!
地下室都变屋顶了
My basement is in the attic.
科学博物馆也毁了
The science museum is history.
这场混乱造成了上千例的死亡
We're lost thousand in this messy.
发生什么事了啊 市长先生?
What's going on Mr. Mayor?
我宣布一个紧急状况
I'm declaring a state of emergency.
别担心 别担心
Don't worry. Don't worry.
市长是蠢材嘛
The Mayor is just being a moron.
不 等等 无名镇陷入了非常危险的境地
No wait. Whoville is in terrible danger.
每个人都得到地下储存室去
Everyone needs get down to the underground storage area immediately.
等等 等等 我们来民主投票
Time time. Let's do this democratically.
谁想要无名镇百年纪念的乐趣与荣耀...
Who wants the joy and glory and festivity of the Whocentennial...
如期进行呢?
to proceed as planned?
耶!
Yeah!
还有谁 跟市长一样
And who, like the Mayor,
认为庆祝百年纪念时...
thinks it would be better to spend the Whocentennial...
呆在地下室会更好一些
in an underground storage area?
耶!
Yeah!
等等! 你们得听我的
Wait! You got to listen to me.
我们整个世界有可能会爆炸
Our whole world could explode.
比预想的更快
Much more quickly.
但是不会有这种噪音
And our world wouldn't make that noise.
人们都已经说了 市长先生
The people have spoken Mr. Mayor.
你完了
You're finished.
没人相信你 没人支持你
No one believes you. No one supports you.
- Horton信任我  - Horton?
- Horton believes me.  - Horton?
Horton是谁?
Who's Horton?
Horton是天空中的一头巨象
Horton is a giant elephant in the sky.
不要费心去看了 你们看不见的
Don't bother look. He is invisible.
他正冒着生命危险
And he is the one risking his life...
来保护无名镇
to get Whoville which by the way...
一粒在苜蓿上的灰尘的平安
is a speck on a clover just safety.
我可以证明
I can prove it.
Horton的声音就是从这个号角里面传出来的
Horton's voice comes out of this horn.
Horton!
我把所有的无名氏都集合在操场上了
I have all the Whos gathered in town square.
让他们知道你的存在
Let them know you there.
哎呀
Gee.
还真有蛮大的压力呢
It's a kind of high pressure situation then.
哇 我一时之间还真不知道说什么呢
Wow. I'm really run a blank here.
我知道了
I know.
Horton?
Horton 我们都在等着呢
Horton, We're waiting.
是时候向大家证明你的存在
Time to show everyone that you exist and...
以及我并不是蠢材了
By extension what a none boob I am.
等等!
Wait!
大家快看 有风 你认为这代表什么呢?
Everyone look at the wind. What do you think that means?
代表 呃 代表... 显然 呃...
It means, Um, it means... obviously, uh...
风筝竞赛开始啦!
Let's the Kite Flying Race begins!
多么高的山啊 Horton! 哈 哈 哈!
What a perron on you Horton! Ha Ha Ha!
呜 脑袋冻住了!
Woo, brain freeze!
还给我...
Give Me Back...
- 我的灰尘!  - 不行 伙计
- My Speck!  - Not this time, guy.
很抱歉让你失望了 但是...
I'm so sorry that I let you down, but...
这... 这件事比我的生命更重要
this... this is bigger than me.
把家人集合在一起 带到安全的地方去
Get the famliy together and get some where safe.
我会的!
I will!
我相信你
I believe you.
可以解决掉你了 白痴
I've got you now, innocent.
不 不 不!
No, No, No!
不
Oh, no.
呼! 喔
Huk! Eung.
耶! 哈哈哈哈...
Yeah! Hahahahaha...
啊哈哈哈....
AhHahahaha....
市长?
Mayor?
有人在吗?
Anybody there?
有人吗?
Anyone?
他一朵一朵苜蓿的找
But clover by clover by clover he found
但是他要寻找的那朵却不在
But the one that he sought for was just not around.
市长?
Mayor?
嗨?
Hello?
直到中午
And by noon
可怜的Horton经历重重困难
poor Horton more dead and alive,
摘了 搜寻了 整理了9005朵花
Had picked, searched, and filed up 9005.
嗨
Hello.
抱歉打扰你了
Sorry to bother you.
没人
Nobody.
敲门 有人在吗
Knock knock.
这就是你采取的方法
This is the way you take.
无名氏?
Whos there?
如果无名氏在那里的话
If there were any Whos there,
你懂了吗? 无名氏在那里
You get it! Whos there.
我不能把你跟这些花放在一起
I can't give up have them with you.
他整天都在找 找啊找
All day he looked. Looked on and on.
在希望即将破灭时
Till his hope was almost gone.
不 不 不 不要啊
No. No. No. Please No!
啊 太不公平了!
Ah, This is unfiar!
等等!
But wait!
这会不会就是那一朵? 大搜寻终于结束了?
Could this one be the one? Was all this searching finally done?
啊 是的 正是此刻...
Ah, yes, for this was the hour...
Horton在三百万朵花中找到了
Horton have found from the 3 millions flowers.
市长?
Mayor?
市长! 我终于找到你!
Mayor! I found you!
市长?
Mayor?
你在吗?
Are you there?
镇长
Mayor.
镇长!
Mayor!
镇长 你在吗?
Mayor, are you there?
镇长
Mayor.
镇长!
Mayor!
啊 不 我是Floyd
Ah, no. This is Floyd.
要我传话吗?
Can I take a message?
镇长!
Mayor!
你没事!
You're Okay!
Horton! Horton! 停下! 别跳了!
Horton! Horton! Stop! Stop it!
抱歉
Sorry.
你们那边一定不太好受吧
It must have been very rough down there.
真不敢相信我居然找到你们了
I can't believe I've found you.
你们真让我好担心
You really have me worried.
瞧啊 镇长是对的!
Say. The Mayor was right!
爸爸 爸爸 爸爸
Daddy, daddy, daddy
好的 我没事 你们也是
OK. I'm alright and so are you.
无名镇的居民们!
Citizens of Whoville!
我想向你们引见我们的朋友 Horton
I'd like you to meet our friend Horton.
他将帮助我们
He's going to help us.
咳咳 让我来说
Heevham I've got this.
我是主席
This is the chairman.
白痴! 你在这个镇里的统治已经结束了
Idiot! You're finished this town.
明白了吗? 结束了 你这个笨蛋!
Is that understood? Finished. You Boob!
呵呵 我开玩笑的
Huhuh I'm just joking.
很搞笑
Good one.
Horton 这是我的妻子Sally
Horton, this is my wife Sally.
你真的存在! 这说明我的丈夫没有发疯
You exist! This means my husband isn't in crazy.
万岁!
Hooray!
接着... 向你介绍我的女儿们
And... off you my daughters.
- Haley Holy Hooly Hilder 还有Heddy  - 嗨!
- Haley, Holy, Hooly, Hilder and Heddy.  - Hi!
这位是Yelp小姐 我忠诚的助手
And here is Miss. Yelp, my loyal assistant.
- 这位是Larue博士  - 你拯救了我们
- And here's Dr. Larue.  - You saved us.
还有会计Bert 还有McQuilligan太太
And Bert from accounting. And Mrs. McQuilligan.
以及来自Cloogan Farfoogans的Farfoogans先生
And Mr. Farfoogan from the Cloogan Farfoogans.
这位浴缸中的老先生
And the old man in bathtub.
别太勉强我们可怜的小伙子了
Let's not overwhelm the poor fella.
他不可能记得住这么多名字的
He's never gonna remember all these names.
好吧 我尽力
Well. I'll try my best.
Sally
Sally.
主席
Chairman.
Haley Hooly Holy Hilder Heddy
Haley, Hooly, Holy, Hilder, Heddy.
Yelp小姐 Larue博士
Miss Yelp, Dr. Larue,
会计Bert McQuilligany太太
Bert from accounting, Mrs. McQuilligany,
Cloogan Farfoogans来的Farfoogan先生
Mr. Farfoogan of the Cloogan Farfoogans.
是不是还有一位在淋浴的老先生
And wan't there an old guy in a shower.
- 嗯 是在浴缸里  - 哦 没错!
- Um, bathtub.  - Oh, Yeah!
我们都在这儿了 Horton
We're all here, Horton.
我们大家都相信你
And, We all believe in you.
Wow! That's awesome.
哇! 那真是太棒了
And it's reponsibility I do not take lightly.
我会认真承担起这个责任
我承诺 将你们领向安全 安定 安稳的未来
I promise you a future that it's safe, sound, and stable.
我们会创造一个这样的世界 那里每个无名氏都会享有三项不容侵犯的权利
We will create a world where every Who is undoubt with 3 inalienable rights...
权利的内容日后再做决定
To be determined that a later date.
And we will put a speck on Mountain Nool before the end of this, uh, decade.
我们将定居在Nool山山顶 在... 呃 十年之内
Oh!
这就是那只疯了的大象 我的天啊
This, this is the elephant who is crazy. Oh my goodness.
我得去告诉谁 我想该去告诉袋鼠
I got to tell anyone. I think it's the kangaroo.
快点找到他们
Quick to they find out of them.
哈哈 你应该看看当时的情形
Hoho, you should've been seeing me.
我摸清了那只大象的习性
I really read the elephant habit.
我对他穷追不舍 百般折磨 然后将他碎尸万段
I chase him, I torment him and then I break him into million little elephant pieces.
那真是美好的景象 我的最佳作品
It was thing of beauty, Really. My best work.
Vlad之经典
Classic Vlad.
- 那苜蓿呢?  - 苜蓿也收拾了
- And the colver?　 - Clover is finished.
No vain million years Horton finds it.
Horton找个千万年都是徒劳的
相信我的话 苜蓿永远的消失了
Believe my beak. Clover is gone forever.
我刚见到Horton了 他还在跟那朵苜蓿说话
I just saw Horton. And he is still talking to that clover.
白痴!
Idiot!
好了 别这样
Whoa, come on.
等等 兄弟 你在跟我说话呢 我们可是有交情的
Hang you, Bro. It's me you're talking to. We have history.
Come on. Let's don't forget I did this for Free.
别忘了我是免费这么做的
What is happening to the jungle of Nool?
Nool丛林里发生什么了?
曾几何时 人就是人
There once was a time when people were people.
灰尘就是灰尘
And specks were specks.
我说过的 如果你看不到 听不到
Well, I say, you can't see it, hear it,
感觉不到 那就是不存在的
or feel it it doesn't exist.
我们的生活方式正受到攻击
Our way of life is under attack.
那么谁是攻击的主谋?
And who's leading that attack?
Horton!
停 停! 等一下!
Horton whoa, whoa! Wait a minute!
This is Horton we're talking about you'll know about him.
我们谈论的可是Horton 你们都了解他
他连一只苍蝇都不忍伤害
He wouldn't hurt a fly.
除了那个被他坐上去的苍蝇窝
Except for that fly city he sat on.
他也不是故意那样做的
He didn't that on purpose.
- 闭嘴 老鼠  - 哦 是的 那真是很怪异
- Shut up, mouse.  - Oh, Yeah. That's weird.
我感觉头脑发热 我得走了
I feel my brain is burning. I got to go.
我们要让Horton那样的祸害
Are we going to let troublemakers
毒害孩子们的心灵吗?
like Horton poison the minds of children?
不能伤害孩子们!
Not the children!
Horton告诉孩子们丛林之外事情的同时
When Horton tells our children about worlds beyond the jungle,
令他们质疑了我们的权威
it makes them question authority.
Which leads to the fires, which leads to shocking!
这会导致混乱 这会导致灾祸!
Yeah! Horton must pay!
没错! Horton要付出代价!
吃掉那颗灰尘!
Eat that speck!
我们要采取行动!
We have to do something!
- 为了孩子们!  - 为了孩子们!
- For the children!  - For the children!
我们能让他逃脱惩罚吗?
Are we going to let him get away with this?
不!
No!
Morton! 我告诉过你我会百分百守信!
Morton! I told you 100%!
Horton
- Morton 脚步轻点儿 天呐  - 不是我
- Morton, pick up your feet, Gee.  - It's not me.
哦 呵呵 我明白了 是群愤怒的暴民
Oh, Hoho. I see. It's an angry mob.
抱歉 Morton
Sorry Morton.
我还以为是你闹出这么大动静...
I thought it's you who's making all the...
但是这...
But it's...
等等
Hold on.
快跑 Horton!
Run, Horton!
他在那里!
There he is!
绑住他!
Let's rope him!
抓住他!
Let's take him!
停!
Stop!
嘿 伙计们
Hey, fellas.
很高兴见到你们
Good to see ya.
还一次见到这么多人
All at once.
你们聚在一起 看上去气色不错
You're look really great as herd.
Horton, Horton, Horton look at that mess you created for yourself.
Horton Horton Horton 看看你给你自己整的烂摊子
我们这样兴师动众 都是因为一朵傻傻的小花
All this hullabaloo over us is a silly little flower.
这是一粒灰尘
It's a speck.
好吧
Right.
我是说 讨论把你捆起来关进笼子 实在是太傻了
I mean it's silly, really, all this talk of roping you and caging you and well
我们不需要详谈
we don't need to go into the details.
关键是你惹怒了这群乡亲们
The point is this angry mob of all a trouble you're in.
这都可以一笔勾销
It can all go away.
- 真的?  - 当然
- Really?  - Of course.
你只需要向大家承认
All you have to do is admit to everyone
那粒灰尘上没有什么小人国
that there are no little people living on that speck.
承认你是错的 而我是对的
That you're wrong and I was right.
你那样做了
You do that,
一切就能像原来那样
and things can go the right back to the way they were.
但如果你不那样做
But, if you don't,
你就将为此付出代价
You're going to have to pay the price.
我只需要说 这不是真的就行了?
So I just have to say it isn't true?
随便你们! 把我捆起来! 把我关起来! 你们想怎么做都行!
Go ahead! Rope me! Cage me! Do whatever you want!
But there are people on this speck.
但是这粒灰尘上确实有人
And they have Mayor.
他们还有一名镇长
他有96个女儿和一个叫做JoJo的儿子
Who has 96 daughters and one son name JoJo,
他们共用一个卫生间 不管那是怎样的
Who all share a bathroom whatever that is.
即使你们无法听到他们 看到他们
And even though you can't hear or see them at all,
生命就是生命 不管有多渺小
Person's a person, no matter how small.
That was beautiful, Horton.
那也很美好 Horton
把他捆起来! 关起来!
Rope him! Cage him!
把那粒灰尘丢到油锅里!
Burn that speck in a pot of boiling pees on that oil!
他们不相信我们在这儿
They don't believe we're here.
我们要弄出些声响!
We've got to make some noise!
我们在这儿 我们在这儿 我们在这儿
We are here. We are here. We are here.
一起来!
Come on!
大家一起来!
Everybody!
我们在这儿 我们在这儿 我们在这儿
We are here. We are here. We are here.
这就是你编故事 说灰尘里住着人的代价!
This is what takes you never make up stories about people on specks!
听啊 他们在说话!
Listen. There they are!
- 捆住他!  - 把他关起来!
- Rope him!  - Cage him!
这不管用
It's not working.
我能听见你们 但是他们的听力不够敏锐
I can hear you. But, their ears aren't strong enough.
我们要更大声
We need to be louder.
每个无名镇居民都要制造声响! 每个人!
Get every Who'd make noise! Everyone!
我们在这儿 我们在这儿 我们在这儿
We are here. We are here. We are here.
JoJo, where're you going?
JoJo 你要去哪儿?
我们需要每个人的声音 JoJo!
We need every voice, JoJo!
你得制造些声响 否则我们都完蛋了
You need to make some noise down there. Or we all be destroyed.
镇长拿起鼓槌 开始敲鼓
The Mayor grabbed the tamtam starting to smack it.
所有无名镇居民 都想方设法发出巨响
And all over Whoville, They ooped up all racket.
他们敲着锡鼓 打着铜锅
They rattle tin kettles, they beat on brass pans,
拍着垃圾桶盖 敲着旧酸莓罐子
On garbage-fill tops, old cranberry cans.
他们吹响"哔哔叭叭铜号"
They blew on byzu bilzl brasstic big tubas.
奏响"嘀嘀哒哒长笛"
On druming Soompazum, Boompazum, plutes
好了!
There!
现在他们能听见了吗?
Can they hear us now?
听啊! 求你了!
Listen! Please!
这是最美的声音!
It's the most beautiful thing ever!
我什么没听到!
I don't hear nothing!
我不这么想
I don't think so.
再试试
But, keep trying.
我不会屈服的!
I'll never give...in!
你确定无名镇上每个无名氏都加入了吗?
Are you sure that every Who down in the Whoville is trying?
JoJo在哪儿?
Where's JoJo?
可能在老天文台
Probably up the old observatory.
Hey, there's our limit.
嘿 挤不进去了
That's not supposed to stretch that far!
鼻子不能那样拉啊!
JoJo!
这是你建的?
You built this?
我们在这儿 我们在这儿 我们在这儿
We are here. We are here. We are here.
你们在犯错
You're making a mistake.
- Mom!  - This doesn't concern you, sweety. Back in your pouch!
- 妈妈!  - 这不关你的事 宝贝儿 回到袋子里去!
大家不要停!
Everybody, don't stop!
继续! 这样能成功的!
Keep going! This gonna do it!
- 他们能听见吗?  - 不能!
- Can they hear?  - No!
不管发生什么 你都是我最好的儿子
No matter what happens, I couldn't ask for a better son.
啊 嘿 JoJo?
Ah, hey, JoJo?
加油! 继续坚持!
Come on! Keep going!
不!
NO!
我们在这儿 我们在这儿 我们在这儿
We are here.We are here.We are here.
不要
No.
我们在这儿 我们在这儿 我们在这儿
We are here.We are here.We are here.
不!
NO!
我们在这儿 我们在这儿 我们在这儿
We are here.We are here.We are here.
我听见了! 我听见了! 他们真的存在!
I hear it! I hear it! They are there!
那一声叫喊
And that yelp.
That one small extra yelp put it over.
那小小的 意外的一声叫喊结束了这一切
无名氏们的声音从苜蓿里迸发出来
And all the Who noises brust out of the clover.
- I hear it, too.  - Me too, wide.
- 我也听见了  - 我也听见了
Rudy. Give me that! Come Ru...
Rudy 把那给我! 给我 Ru...
Rudy 回到育儿袋去 马上
Rudy, get back in the pouch now.
不要 妈妈
No, Mom.
Wickersam兄弟 拿下那朵苜蓿
Uh, Wickersams, get that clover.
怎么... 随便来个人 从他手里拿下苜蓿
What the...E..Anybody take it from him.
你们成功了 镇长
You did it, Mayor.
你们成功了
You did it.
我们成功了!
We did it!
耶!!
Yeah!
干得漂亮 儿子
Well done, son.
太棒了 镇长!
Alright, Mayor!
爸爸 你成为了伟人之一
Dad, you're one of the Greats.
哇! 大家放轻松 轻松点!
Wow! Easy everyone. Easy!
哦 你好 Vlad
Oh hi, Vlad.
我不该这样 但是...
Well, I shouldn't. But,
哦 老兄 这真是感人
Oh man, that is nice touch.
我不吃这一套 我可不多愁善感
I'm a mess with this. I am not emotional.
只是有水流出来了
Here comes the water slide.
如果有要感谢的人
And someone if you want thank
那就是Nool的好人们
The good people of nool
你们把我关进笼子 还用棍子戳我
who put me on a cage and poke me with sticks
那是我哦!
That was me!
还要感谢唯一支持我的兄弟
My buddy more than for being the only who stood by me.
好吧 虽然不是正面支持 他一直躲在树丛里
Well, not right by me he's hidden in the bushs
给我善意的提醒
Sending me good thoughts.
他很小
He's small.
Dude. You're a warrior poet.
兄弟 你真是个战争诗人
我最要感谢的 是无名镇的镇长
And most of all I'd like to thank to the Mayor of Whoville.
- 他从始至终相信我  - 哦 Horton
- Who believed me from the beginning.  - Oh, Horton.
We're going to miss you.
我们会想念你的
呵呵 哎呀
Hmm. Gee
没有了你我们怎么办 Horton?
What are we gonna do without you, Horton?
啊 别担心
Ah, don't worry.
我会一直在你们身边
I always be around.
# 即使我迷惑彷徨 #
# And even as I wonder, #
# I'll keep you in sight. #
# 我仍会注视着你 #
# 你是窗内的烛光 #
#  Keeping in them sight. #
- # 在寒冷的冬夜 #  - 比喻真巧妙
- # On a cool dark winter's night. #  - Beautiful metaphor.
# 我比想象的还要接近你 #
# And I'm getting closer than I ever thought I might. #
哦 那个音调有点高了
Uh, that's a little high funny.
# Baby, I can't fight this feeling any more. #
# 宝贝 我再也无法控制这感觉 #
# 我忘记了我为什么开始奋斗 #
# I've forgotten what I started fighting for. #
# 如果我不得不匍匐向前 #
# And if I have to crawl upon the floor. #
- # 冲进你的家门 #  - # 冲进你的家门 #
- # Come crashing through your door. #  - # Crashing through your door. #
# Baby I can't fight this feeling any more. #
# 宝贝 我再也无法控制这感觉 #
# 我再也无法控制这感觉 #
# I can't fight this feeling any more. #
对于霍顿与无名氏来说 故事结束得十分完满
And so all ended well for those Horton and Whos.
对于丛林里的所有人 甚至包括袋鼠也同样如此
And for all in the jungle, even Kangaroos.
So let that be a lesson to one and to all.
让我们每个人都认识这样一个道理吧
生命就是生命
A person's a person.
No matter how small.
无论其多么渺小